<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>L&amp;L Lab</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on L&amp;L Lab</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About our Lab</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>How do we learn language? Children acquire this knowledge so quickly, and we sometimes forget how incredible this is. The goal of our research is to better understand the mechanisms underlying the mastery of linguistic knowledge. Recent advances in our ability to study large, naturalistic datasets, combined with advanced computational modeling techniques, have allowed us to ask questions that were not possible just years before. One of the major insights from our work is that “Big Data” research that investigates the structure of experience – such as investigations of giant corpora of naturalistic speech – will force us to radically re-evaluate certain theories of learning and representation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join</title>
      <link>/join/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/join/</guid>
      <description>Graduate Students Both Dr. Montag and Dr. Willits are recruiting graduate students to begin in Fall 2019. For additional information about how to apply, see the Illinois Psychology Department website.
Post-Docs The lab will be recruiting a post-doc to begin Fall 2019. The research focus for this position will be computational modeling of learning and language. The ideal candidate will have previous experience in computational modeling, natural language processing, and programming in Python.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Members</title>
      <link>/members/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/members/</guid>
      <description>Principal Investigators Dr. Jessica L. Montag Email: jmontag@illinois.edu
Website: http://languagestats.com/jessicamontag/
Jessica Montag studies how language abilities emerge with experience across the lifespan, including language comprehension, production, and reading. Dr. Montag uses varied methods and measures, including comprehension and production experiments in adults and children, compilation and analyses of text and speech corpora, and advanced quantitative methods.
Dr. Jon A. Willits Email: jwillits@illinois.edu
Website: http://languagestats.com/jonwillits/
Jon Willits studies language and learning in infants, children, adults, and machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participate</title>
      <link>/participate/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/participate/</guid>
      <description>Volunteers Needed for Our Research! If you have a child between about 6 months and 6 years old, we&amp;rsquo;d be thrilled if you and your child would participate in our studies of learning and language. Children are learning vast amounts of information from the earliest moments. We study how children learn language and other kinds of knowledge, including what words mean, how to talk and understand language, and how to read.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description>Peer-reviewed Papers Montag, J. L. (2019). Differences in sentence complexity in the text of children’s picture books and child-directed speech. First Language, 1-20.
Huebner, P., &amp;amp; Willits, J. (2018). Structured semantic knowledge can emerge automatically from predicting word sequences in child-directed speech. Frontiers in Psychology, 9, 133.
Minor, K. S., Willits, J. A., Marggraf, M. P., Jones, M. N. (2018) Measuring disorganized speech in schizophrenia: automated analysis explains variance in cognitive deficits beyond clinician-rated scales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/</guid>
      <description>Documentation File sharing https://docs.philhuebner.com</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools</title>
      <link>/tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/tools/</guid>
      <description>Data &amp;amp; Tools Open-Source Python Packages Preppy Website: https://github.com/phueb/Preppy</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topics</title>
      <link>/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/research/</guid>
      <description>Recent works by topic (2016-) Language Production Montag, J. L., Matsuki, K., Kim, J. &amp;amp; MacDonald, M. C. (2017). The effects of word order on sentence structure choice in language production: A multi-clause and multi-language investigation. Collabra: Psychology, 3, 20.
MacDonald, M. C., Montag, J. L., &amp;amp; Gennari, S. P. (2016). Are there really syntactic complexity effects in sentence production?: A reply to Scontras et al. Cognitive Science, 40, 513-518.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>